<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>continous on Shaaf, Syed's blog</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/tags/continous/</link><description>Recent content in continous on Shaaf, Syed's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 16:31:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shaaf.dev/tags/continous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automation with Selenium,Junit, Ant</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/post/2009-01-19-automation-with-seleniumjunit-ant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 16:31:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://shaaf.dev/post/2009-01-19-automation-with-seleniumjunit-ant/</guid><description>Much of the technologies above do not or will not need an introduction if you already know them or can read them from the links above.
More over today&amp;rsquo;s article is more about how we can use all the three selenium, ant and junit to come up with an automated solution for regressive testing.
Please refer to the documentation links above for the basic knowledge on any of the used tools.</description></item><item><title>Continous Integration - A blast from the past</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/post/2008-11-12-continous-integration-a-blast-from-the-past/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 20:00:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://shaaf.dev/post/2008-11-12-continous-integration-a-blast-from-the-past/</guid><description>Although this didn&amp;rsquo;t happen a decade ago but still has been a good case for me to learn and realize how Continuous Integration brings value addition to our work.
As I recall it was like this when they were teenagers :D Few teams working on different modules of same application, deployed together. No build process formalized No builds except for the ones that need major milestone deployments. No feedback, reports, reviews etc.</description></item><item><title>That thing about CI - Continous Integration</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/post/2008-11-12-that-thing-about-ci-continous-integration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 14:11:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://shaaf.dev/post/2008-11-12-that-thing-about-ci-continous-integration/</guid><description>Challenging Business requirements and the need for software development teams to remain agile and competitive while managing parallel development and releases requires a system which is adaptive to these demands.
Our approach to SCM enables unlimited and adaptable process models, which are ideally suited for parallel, distributed, and agile software development. Using state of the Art technologies from various vendors to automate processes such as branching, merging, build, and release keeps you a click away from software delivery.</description></item></channel></rss>