<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>redhat on Shaaf, Syed's blog</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/tags/redhat/</link><description>Recent content in redhat on Shaaf, Syed's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 07:07:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shaaf.dev/tags/redhat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SQL cache stores and more in Data Grid 8.3</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/post/2022-02-24-sql-cache-stores-and-more-data-grid-83/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 07:07:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://shaaf.dev/post/2022-02-24-sql-cache-stores-and-more-data-grid-83/</guid><description>Orignally posted at Red Hat Developers
Red Hat Data Grid is a distributed, cloud-based datastore offering very fast response times as an in-memory database. The latest version, Data Grid 8.3, features cross-site replication with more observability and two new types of SQL cache store for scaling applications with large datasets. This version also brings improved security, support for Helm charts, and a better command-line interface (CLI).
This article is an overview of new features and enhancements in this latest version of Red Hat Data Grid.</description></item><item><title>What's new for developers in Java 18</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/post/2022-01-27-whats-new-for-developers-in-java-18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 07:07:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://shaaf.dev/post/2022-01-27-whats-new-for-developers-in-java-18/</guid><description>Orignally posted at Red Hat Developers
In exciting news for Java developers, Java 18 forked off from the main line at the end of last year and has entered Rampdown Phase Two. This article highlights some of the features that developers can look for in the upcoming Java 18 release, including the new simple web server module, a more sophisticated way to annotate your Javadocs, and the –finalization=disabled option, which lets you test how a Java application will behave when finalization is removed in a future release.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Quarkus everywhere with Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL)</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/post/2021-05-17-deploy-quarkus-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 07:07:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://shaaf.dev/post/2021-05-17-deploy-quarkus-everywhere/</guid><description>Orignally posted at Red Hat Developers
Java is one of the most used languages out there and has been in the top three for the last two decades. Java powers millions of applications across verticals and platforms. Linux is widely deployed in data centers, Edge networks, and Cloud. Today we announce the availability of Quarkus for all our Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) customers. If you are running RHEL, you can now also run Red Hat Build of Quarkus (RHBQ).</description></item><item><title>Creating and deploying a Java 8 runtime container image</title><link>https://shaaf.dev/post/2019-02-26-create-java-8-runtime-container-image/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 07:07:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://shaaf.dev/post/2019-02-26-create-java-8-runtime-container-image/</guid><description>Orignally posted at Red Hat Developers
A Java runtime environment should be able to run compiled source code, whereas a development kit, for example, OpenJDK, would include all the libraries/binaries to compile and run the source code. Essentially the latter is a superset of the runtime environment. More details on OpenJDK support and lifecycle can be found here.
Red Hat ships and supports container images with OpenJDK for both Java 8 and 11.</description></item></channel></rss>